Guide to the Records of the College of Engineering, Research Division RG.24.1
New York University Archives
Records of the College of Engineering, Research Division
1936-1964
New York University Archives
New York University. College of Engineering
RG.24.1
1.60 Linear Feet in 3 manuscript boxes and 1 folder in a shared box.
The New York University School of Engineering was founded in 1854 as the School of Civil Engineering and Architecture. In 1973, the School merged with the Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn. The Records of the College of Engineering, Research Division (dated 1936-1964) documents the College's research output, and includes project reports, as well as policy and procedure documents.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
These materials were removed from the New York University Archives Collection of Publications and Ephemera (MC 334) during processing; their original provenance is unknown.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. Original order is unknown.
Historical Note
The New York University School of Engineering was founded in 1854 as the School of Civil Engineering and Architecture. In 1973, the School merged with the Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn.
Scope and Contents
The Records of the College of Engineering, Research Division (1936-1964) documents the College's research output, and includes project reports, as well as policy and procedure documents.
Engineering -- Study and teaching; Engineering; Engineering -- History
- Promotional Brochures, 1956-1958 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- "Notes on Elementary Fluid Machines" (John King Vennard), 1936 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- "Advanced Strength of Materials" (Ferdinand L. Singer), 1937 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Wind Turbines Report, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Multiple Reports, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Cosmic Ray Group Reports, 1955-1964 (Box 1, Folder 6, Box 2, Folder 1-6, Box 3, Folder 1-3)
- Geiger Counter Project, 1953-1958 (Box 3, Folder 4-9)
- Policies and Procedures Handbook, 1950-1951 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Research Policy Guide, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Research Policy, undated (Box Shared University Archives 149, Folder 10)